const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Molecules that have the same molecular formula but different structures are known as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Isomer","bool":true},{"option":"Isotopes","bool":false},{"option":"Anomer","bool":false},{"option":"Isopod","bool":false},{"option":"Asymmetric","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Carbohydrates that differ in configuration around a single carbon atom are known as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Enantiomers","bool":false},{"option":"Epimers","bool":true},{"option":"Cis isomers","bool":false},{"option":"Stereoisomers","bool":false},{"option":"Optical isomers","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of these is a sulfur-containing amino acid?","answers":[{"option":"Alanine","bool":false},{"option":"Serine","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Cysteine","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is true for strong acids?","answers":[{"option":"Their Ka is low","bool":false},{"option":"They dissociate partially","bool":false},{"option":"Their pH is high","bool":false},{"option":"Their pKa is high","bool":false},{"option":"Their pKa is low","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which amino acid can disrupt helical structure?","answers":[{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Proline","bool":true},{"option":"Alanine","bool":false},{"option":"Valine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What do the properties of fatty acids depend on?","answers":[{"option":"Both chain length and degree of saturation","bool":true},{"option":"Size of carbon atoms","bool":false},{"option":"Chain length","bool":false},{"option":"Both size of carbon atoms and chain length","bool":false},{"option":"Degree of saturation","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Spermatogenesis is regulated by which hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Androgens and estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone and luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone and estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone and estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) and testosterone","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which cells are responsible for the production of testosterone?","answers":[{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus cells","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate gland cells","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior pituitary cells","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is the most common site of ectopic pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Intramural uterine tube","bool":false},{"option":"Isthmus of the fallopian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Rectouterine pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Ampulla of the uterine tube","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following substances is formed due to the esterification of fatty acids with long-chain alcohols?","answers":[{"option":"Waxes","bool":true},{"option":"Fatty alcohols","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":false},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Triglycerides","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following  underlying structures induces the formation of overlying ectoderm into a neural tube?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus pulposus","bool":false},{"option":"Notochord","bool":true},{"option":"Primitive streak","bool":false},{"option":"Neurenteric canal","bool":false},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A 1st year medical student is given a slide of the ureter. Which type of epithelium is present in the lining of the ureter?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudostratified epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Stratified columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"The deficiency of which of the following minerals is seen in Menkes disease, an X-linked recessive disorder, involving the defective cross-linking of collagen and elastic fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Manganese","bool":false},{"option":"Copper","bool":true},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Zinc","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following structures is not drained by the thoracic duct?","answers":[{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Right half of head and neck","bool":true},{"option":"Left half of head and neck","bool":false},{"option":"Right lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Left lower limb","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"At what site, within an enzyme, does the catalytic action of an enzyme generally take place?","answers":[{"option":"Co-factor","bool":false},{"option":"Co-enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Active site","bool":true},{"option":"Prosthetic group","bool":false},{"option":"Protein part","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following structures do not have lymphatic drainage?","answers":[{"option":"Inguinal region","bool":false},{"option":"Brain","bool":true},{"option":"Intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Axilla","bool":false},{"option":"Breast","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"An old lady falls down the stairs and fractures her hip bone. Which type of joint is a hip joint?","answers":[{"option":"Condylar joint","bool":false},{"option":"Hinge joint","bool":false},{"option":"Ball and socket joint","bool":true},{"option":"Pivot joint","bool":false},{"option":"Saddle joint","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is a sulfur-containing amino acid?","answers":[{"option":"Methionine","bool":true},{"option":"Proline","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Serine","bool":false},{"option":"Arginine","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"In which form is provitamin A found in vegetables?","answers":[{"option":"Retinol","bool":false},{"option":"Calciferol","bool":false},{"option":"1,25 dihydroxy cholecalciferol","bool":false},{"option":"Beta carotene","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha tocopherol","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following differentiates meiosis from mitosis?","answers":[{"option":"The gametes produced are diploid","bool":false},{"option":"Two daughter cells are produced","bool":false},{"option":"Occurs in germ cells","bool":true},{"option":"Occurs in somatic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Crossing over does not take place","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"At what stage does crossing over occur in meiosis?","answers":[{"option":"Prophase II","bool":false},{"option":"Prophase I","bool":true},{"option":"Anaphase I","bool":false},{"option":"Metaphase II","bool":false},{"option":"Anaphase II","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is the term for the movement of water molecules across a semi-permeable membrane into a region of high solute concentration?","answers":[{"option":"Osmosis","bool":true},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Active transport","bool":false},{"option":"Diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Endocytosis","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Gastrulation is the process involving the conversion of the bilaminar disc to trilaminar disc. Which is the first morphological sign for gastrulation?","answers":[{"option":"Development of primitive streak","bool":true},{"option":"Development of neural plate","bool":false},{"option":"Development of notochord","bool":false},{"option":"Development of prechordal plate","bool":false},{"option":"Development of neural tube","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Protection is a function of epithelial cells. Which type of epithelial cells are primarily responsible for it?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous epithelium (non-keratinized)","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous epithelium (keratinized)","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following processes requires energy?","answers":[{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Filtration","bool":false},{"option":"Simple diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytosis","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A person loses sensation at the anterior surface of the forearm. The neurons involved in the transmission of signals from here to the central nervous system are of which type?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar","bool":false},{"option":"Multipolar","bool":false},{"option":"Motor neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudounipolar","bool":true},{"option":"Interneuron","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following takes part in the regulation of gene expression?","answers":[{"option":"ssRNA","bool":false},{"option":"mRNA","bool":false},{"option":"rRNA","bool":false},{"option":"tRNA","bool":false},{"option":"miRNA","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A first-year medical student was nervous when taking their viva exam. How will this student's autonomic nervous system respond?","answers":[{"option":"Increased gastrointestinal mobility","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Constriction of pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Increased heart rate","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchoconstriction","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which neurotransmitter is released at preganglionic and postganglionic nerve terminals of the parasympathetic nervous system respectively?","answers":[{"option":"Epinephrine and acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine and acetylcholine","bool":true},{"option":"Acetylcholine and epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine and norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine and acetylcholine","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which type of enzymes transfers functional groups?","answers":[{"option":"Transferases","bool":true},{"option":"Lyases","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxylases","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrolases","bool":false},{"option":"Oxidases","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Tyrosine falls under which class of amino acids?","answers":[{"option":"Basic","bool":false},{"option":"Simple","bool":false},{"option":"Essential","bool":false},{"option":"Non-essential","bool":true},{"option":"Acidic","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A girl was brought to the hospital after she fell while playing and could not move her knee. After examination, it was told that the joint between the epiphysis and diaphysis of the tibia has been dislocated. Which type of joint is it?","answers":[{"option":"Gomphosis","bool":false},{"option":"Primary cartilaginous (synchondroses)","bool":true},{"option":"Secondary cartilaginous (symphysis)","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrous","bool":false},{"option":"Synovial","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A patient has undergone colonoscopy and esophagoscopy. Cells collected in the biopsy are of non-keratinized stratified squamous epithelium. Which structure contains these cells?","answers":[{"option":"Sigmoid column","bool":false},{"option":"Rectum","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Esophagus","bool":true},{"option":"Colon","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"When neural tube is formed, some cells remain in between the neural plate and the overlying ectoderm. What are these cells called?","answers":[{"option":"Ectodermal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Primitive node cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mesodermal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Notochordal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neural crest cells","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Sacrococcygeal teratoma occurs due to remains of the primitive streak in postnatal life. Primitive streak formation is the first sign of which of these stages?","answers":[{"option":"Cleavage","bool":false},{"option":"Implantation","bool":false},{"option":"Neurulation","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrulation","bool":true},{"option":"Blastulation","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"The student is given a histological section of the gray matter of the brain to observe. The\r\nimage shows cells with multiple cytoplasmic processes spread across. These perivascular cells\r\nalso sit at various places along the capillary endothelium. Which cells are these?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrous astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Microglia","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Protoplasmic astrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A child weighs less than 2.5 kgs when it is born. The delivery is vaginal and the baby is born after 35 weeks of gestation. What is this condition called?","answers":[{"option":"High birth weight","bool":false},{"option":"Low birth weight","bool":true},{"option":"Premature birth","bool":false},{"option":"Post mature birth","bool":false},{"option":"Small gestational age","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What are macrophages in connective tissue known as?","answers":[{"option":"Kupffer cell","bool":false},{"option":"Langerhans cell","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cell","bool":false},{"option":"Dust cell","bool":false},{"option":"Histiocyte","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which type of starch has both α 1-4 linkages and α 1-6 linkages (at branch points)?","answers":[{"option":"Amylose","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Amylopectin","bool":true},{"option":"Cellulose","bool":false},{"option":"Modified starch","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which polymer found in plant cells is a major component of their cell and is also a major constituent of insoluble dietary fiber?","answers":[{"option":"Glycogen","bool":false},{"option":"Cellulose","bool":true},{"option":"Chitin","bool":false},{"option":"Starch","bool":false},{"option":"Dextrin","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A dense connective tissue containing bundles of collagen fibers that run parallel to each other and have only fibroblast cells with flattened nuclei in between them. This tissue is present in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Tendon","bool":true},{"option":"Adipose tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Capsule","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Increased permeability of the membrane to which of the following ions makes the inside of the cell more negative?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium","bool":true},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"In which type of inhibition do a substance bind to the active site and the substrate compete with that substance to occupy the active site?","answers":[{"option":"Allosteric inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Uncompetitive inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Competitive inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Irreversible inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Non-competitive inhibition","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What causes hyperpolarization during an action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Prolonged opening of voltage gated K+ channels","bool":true},{"option":"Sodium leaky channels","bool":false},{"option":"Closure of Cl- channels","bool":false},{"option":"Prolonged opening of voltage gated sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Prolonged closure of K+ ion channels","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is the advantage of the parenteral route?","answers":[{"option":"Cannot be used in emergency","bool":false},{"option":"Takes time to reach the site of action","bool":false},{"option":"Cannot be given to unconscious patients","bool":false},{"option":"Delayed access to systematic circulation","bool":false},{"option":"Greater absorption than oral route","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which is the major glycoprotein of the extracellular matrix that is also soluble in plasma?","answers":[{"option":"Laminin","bool":false},{"option":"Elastin","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen","bool":false},{"option":"Proteoglycan","bool":false},{"option":"Fibronectin","bool":true}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"In prokaryotes, initiation of the transcription involves recognition of the initial site by which factor of RNA polymerase enzyme?","answers":[{"option":"Sigma factor","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha factor","bool":false},{"option":"Enzyme assembly factor","bool":false},{"option":"Beta factor","bool":false},{"option":"Template binding factor","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Beta-pleated sheat in an example of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Primary structure","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary structure","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary structure","bool":true},{"option":"Quaternary structure","bool":false},{"option":"Linear structure","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which is the signaling molecule made from the oxidation of arachidonic acid or other polyunsaturated fats?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphlipid","bool":false},{"option":"Eicosanoid","bool":true},{"option":"Triacylglycerol","bool":false},{"option":"Steroid","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is the ability of the drug to elicit a response after binding to a receptor called?","answers":[{"option":"Potency","bool":false},{"option":"Efficacy","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacology","bool":false},{"option":"Intrinsic activity","bool":true},{"option":"Elimination","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following lens is responsible for gathering and focusing the light on the specimen?","answers":[{"option":"Condenser lens","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Eyepiece lens","bool":false},{"option":"Ocular lens","bool":false},{"option":"Objective lens","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following results in Klinefelter's syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"High maternal age","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Low maternal age","bool":false},{"option":"Radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Drug reaction","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following modes of secretion is used by sebaceous glands?","answers":[{"option":"Apocrine","bool":false},{"option":"Holocrine","bool":true},{"option":"Paracrine","bool":false},{"option":"Merocrine","bool":false},{"option":"Eccrine","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following processes has clathrin as an important factor?","answers":[{"option":"Endocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Osmosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Exocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"An oocyte is arrested at which stage of prophase I of meiosis I?","answers":[{"option":"Zygotene","bool":false},{"option":"Leptotene","bool":false},{"option":"Diakinesis","bool":false},{"option":"Diplotene","bool":true},{"option":"Pachytene","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following has monosomy sex chromosomes?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Edwards syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Turners syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Klinefelters syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Downs syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is correctly matched to its chromosomal genotype?","answers":[{"option":"Klinefelter's -> 45XXY","bool":false},{"option":"Down -> trisomy 18","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelter - > 45XO","bool":false},{"option":"Turner ->  45XO","bool":true},{"option":"Turner -> 47XXXY","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following correctly defines resolution?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Shortest distance between the two points that can be visually distinguished","bool":true},{"option":"Factor by which the image is enlarged","bool":false},{"option":"Largest distance between the two points that can be visually distinguished","bool":false},{"option":"Source of illumination by which the specimen is visualized","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following enzymes is involved in the acrosome reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Acrosin","bool":true},{"option":"Esterase","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrin","bool":false},{"option":"Peptidase","bool":false},{"option":"Glycosidases","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"An infertile couple visits the obstetrician to find out the reason for infertility. Upon examination, the doctor finds out the blockage of the uterine tubes near the peritoneal cavity in the female. Where, in the uterine tube, is the blockage located?","answers":[{"option":"Ampulla","bool":false},{"option":"Infundibulum","bool":true},{"option":"Isthmus","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine ostium","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"The teacher asks the student to stand in an anatomical position. Which of the following correctly defines his position?","answers":[{"option":"Face towards the teacher, standing erect, arms adjacent to sides, palms facing teacher's side","bool":false},{"option":"Face towards the teacher, standing erect, arms adjacent to sides, palms facing backwards","bool":false},{"option":"Face facing forward, standing erect, arms adjacent to sides, palms facing forward","bool":true},{"option":"Face facing forward, standing erect, arms folded, palms facing forward","bool":false},{"option":"Face towards the feet, standing erect, arms adjacent to sides, palms facing backwards","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following junctions is involved in the linkage of adjacent cells and prevention of the movement of extracellular fluid between them?","answers":[{"option":"Desmosome","bool":false},{"option":"Macula adherens","bool":false},{"option":"Tight junction","bool":true},{"option":"Gap junction","bool":false},{"option":"Zonula adheren","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is correct about skeletal muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Each muscle cell is separated by an intercalated disc","bool":false},{"option":"T tubules form a diad with sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"T tubules is in between the A - band and I - band","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Each muscle cell has single nuclei","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following cell organelles has lamins (proteins) in their membrane, consists of DNA and histone, has chromatin, and controls cell division?","answers":[{"option":"Endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Mitochondrion","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi body","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which term refers to the twisting of the foot in the inward direction?","answers":[{"option":"Plantarflexion","bool":false},{"option":"Eversion","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsiflexion","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Inversion","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following cell junctions forms by fusing the outer leaflets of membranes of adjacent cells?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Macula adheren","bool":false},{"option":"Zonula occluden","bool":true},{"option":"Gap junction","bool":false},{"option":"Zonula adheren","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following occurs as a result of parasympathetic fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Ejaculation","bool":false},{"option":"Constriction of bronchi","bool":true},{"option":"Dilation of pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Relaxation of internal anal sphincter","bool":false},{"option":"Tachycardia","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following cells has contractile filaments?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Serous cells","bool":false},{"option":"Blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Myoepithelial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Mucous cells","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What will happen to red blood cells when they are placed in 0.1% sodium chloride solution?","answers":[{"option":"Shrink and burst","bool":false},{"option":"Remain same","bool":false},{"option":"Swell and burst","bool":true},{"option":"Swell only","bool":false},{"option":"Shrink","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following fatty acids is the precursor of the prostaglandins?","answers":[{"option":"Eicosapentaenoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Arachidonic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Linolenic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Omega-3 fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Linoleic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following contributes to the fluidity of the cell membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Unsaturated fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Triacylglycerol","bool":false},{"option":"Long chain saturated fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":true},{"option":"Short chain saturated fatty acids","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is correct for the histology of muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Voluntary muscles are non-striated","bool":false},{"option":"Skeletal muscles have multiple nuclei located centrally","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac muscles have several nuclei at periphery","bool":false},{"option":"M line is present at center of sarcomere","bool":true},{"option":"Cross-section of smooth muscles shows cells with single nuclei located peripherally","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following refers to the affinity of the drug?","answers":[{"option":"Measure of bioavailability of a drug","bool":false},{"option":"Measure of rate at which it is eliminated","bool":false},{"option":"How drug binds to a receptor","bool":true},{"option":"Measure of inhibiting potency of a drug","bool":false},{"option":"How tightly drug binds to plasma proteins","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is an example of a symport co-transporter?","answers":[{"option":"Na-K-2Cl carrier protein","bool":true},{"option":"Sodium hydrogen counter transport","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium calcium counter transport","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen pump","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium potassium pump","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"For which of the following conditions, prenatal diagnosis at fertilization is done?","answers":[{"option":"Goiter","bool":false},{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Marasmus","bool":false},{"option":"Scurvy","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes insipidus","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following occurs in the conjugation process of the bacteria?","answers":[{"option":"Lysis of bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Growth of bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Exchange of genetic material","bool":true},{"option":"Cells joining together to form a bigger cell","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is the term used for the study of natural drugs and their physical and chemical properties?","answers":[{"option":"Pharmacodynamics","bool":false},{"option":"Toxicology","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacy","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacopoeia","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacognosy","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following cells are involved in the production of free radicals in a respiratory burst?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":true},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Natural killer cells","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Proteoglycans are proteins that are covalently bonded to which of the following molecules?","answers":[{"option":"Amino acid","bool":false},{"option":"Amino glycans","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxyl lysine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycosaminoglycan","bool":true},{"option":"Carbohydrate residues","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following forms as a result of the migration of cells from the primitive pit?","answers":[{"option":"Ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Notochord","bool":true},{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Allantois","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following explains Turner syndrome (45XO)?","answers":[{"option":"Disomic condition","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Monosomic condition","bool":true},{"option":"Trisomic condition","bool":false},{"option":"Haploid condition","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following proteins is an example of secondary transport?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium pump","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ pump","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium-glucose co-transporter","bool":true},{"option":"Sodium-potassium pump","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A histopathologist observes the skin slide under a microscope, which shows the hypodermis and papillary layer of the dermis. The connective tissue present in these tissues is which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Irregular","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Loose","bool":true},{"option":"Dense","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following explains community medicine?","answers":[{"option":"Science of application of chemical knowledge","bool":false},{"option":"Aims to increase the number of hospitals","bool":false},{"option":"Art and science of application of technical knowledge","bool":true},{"option":"Application of skills to the delivery of goods to the population","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is the normal osmolarity of the body?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"280 mOsm/L","bool":true},{"option":"300 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"260 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"250 mOsm/L","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is the concentration of Na+ and K+ in the extracellular fluid (ECF) respectively?","answers":[{"option":"Na+=145 mEq/L and K+=4.9 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"Na+=138 mEq/L and K+=4.6 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"Na+=130 mEq/L and K+=5.6mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"Na+=142 mEq/L and K+=4.2 mEq/L","bool":true},{"option":"Na+=140 mEq/L and K+=4.0 mEq/L","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is correct for oogenesis?","answers":[{"option":"Primary oocyte is arrested in metaphase 1 of meiosis until puberty","bool":false},{"option":"Primary oocytes arrested in prophase of meiosis 1 until puberty","bool":true},{"option":"Primary oocyte is arrested in prophase of meiosis 1 until fertilization","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary oocyte is arrested in metaphase of meiosis 1 until fertilization","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary oocyte is arrested in metaphase of meiosis 2 until puberty","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following junctions forms a tube-like structure similar to that of cardiomyocytes?","answers":[{"option":"Occluding junction","bool":false},{"option":"Desmosome","bool":false},{"option":"Gap junction","bool":true},{"option":"Hemidesmosome","bool":false},{"option":"Tight junction","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Okazaki fragments are formed on the ______ strands in the ______ direction.","answers":[{"option":"Lagging, 5'-3'","bool":true},{"option":"Leading, 5'-3'","bool":false},{"option":"Leading, 3'-5'","bool":false},{"option":"Lagging, 3'-5'","bool":false},{"option":"Both same","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Crossing over takes place in which phase of the meiosis?","answers":[{"option":"Leptotene","bool":false},{"option":"Diplotene","bool":false},{"option":"Diakinesis","bool":false},{"option":"Pachytene","bool":true},{"option":"Zygotene","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Wrist belongs to which type of joint?","answers":[{"option":"Condyloid","bool":true},{"option":"Ball and socket","bool":false},{"option":"Hinge","bool":false},{"option":"Uniaxial","bool":false},{"option":"Biaxial","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is responsible for the unwinding of DNA strands for replication?","answers":[{"option":"Single strand DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Helicase","bool":true},{"option":"Topoisomerase","bool":false},{"option":"RNA polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"DNA ligase","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is the function of the endoplasmic reticulum with granules?","answers":[{"option":"Enzyme transport","bool":false},{"option":"Protein assembly","bool":false},{"option":"Protein formation","bool":true},{"option":"Lipid synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Peroxisome formation","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Ovary is lined by which epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":true},{"option":"Stratified squamous","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Dorsum of the tongue is lined by which epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Stratified squamous non-keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous partially keratinized","bool":true},{"option":"Stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is meant by the term pharmacokinetics?","answers":[{"option":"Biological and therapeutic effects of drug","bool":false},{"option":"Absorption, metabolism and excretion of drugs","bool":true},{"option":"Study of identification of drugs","bool":false},{"option":"Methods of new drug development","bool":false},{"option":"Effect of drug on body","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"In the pathology lecture, the procedure of slide preparation was discussed and was emphasized on the fact that slides must be fixed to prevent the substance from degradation by the bacteria. Which of the following is the best fixative for light microscopy?","answers":[{"option":"Alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"Formalin 10%","bool":true},{"option":"Glyceraldehyde","bool":false},{"option":"Osmium tetroxide","bool":false},{"option":"Glycerin","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is the term used for the outer layer of the entire muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Endosteum","bool":false},{"option":"Periosteum","bool":false},{"option":"Perimysium","bool":false},{"option":"Endomysium","bool":false},{"option":"Epimysium","bool":true}]},{"id":98,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"At what temperature does the water have the highest density?","answers":[{"option":"-1°C","bool":false},{"option":"-4°C","bool":false},{"option":"0°C","bool":false},{"option":"4°C","bool":true},{"option":"10°C","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A 20-year-old male presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of loss of vision in the right eye. He further mentions that his brother and cousin also had the same symptoms and were diagnosed with Marfan syndrome.  What is the gene defect in this syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Copper","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrillin 1","bool":true},{"option":"MF 1","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy X","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Quantitatively, which of the following is the most significant buffer system?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphate buffer system","bool":false},{"option":"Protein buffer system","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Carbonic acid-bicarbonate system","bool":true},{"option":"Lactic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which enzyme is responsible for releasing DNA supercoils?","answers":[{"option":"Single strand DNA","bool":false},{"option":"DNA ligase","bool":false},{"option":"Helicase","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerase","bool":true},{"option":"RNA polymerase","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Dystrophic calcification is caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Fractured bones","bool":false},{"option":"Normal calcium levels in blood","bool":false},{"option":"Necrotic tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Bone formation","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperparathyroidism","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which type of cell change occurs due to long-standing hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Metaplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A woman presented to the outpatient department and was positive for β-human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) hormone. Which cells release this hormone?","answers":[{"option":"Syncytiotrophoblast","bool":true},{"option":"Epiblast","bool":false},{"option":"Heuser’s membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotrophoblast","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is a non-invasive technique used for the developing embryo?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic villus sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Pre-implanting genetic diagnosis","bool":false},{"option":"Amniocentesis","bool":false},{"option":"Cordocentesis","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasonography","bool":true}]},{"id":106,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is an example of physiological apoptosis?","answers":[{"option":"Atresia of uterus after menopause","bool":true},{"option":"Scarring after myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Lung abscesses","bool":false},{"option":"Necrotizing fasciitis","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemia","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which process is involved in the DNA damage by mutation?","answers":[{"option":"Conjugation","bool":false},{"option":"Radiation","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Transformation","bool":false},{"option":"Transduction","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which ion is present most abundantly in the intracellular environment?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium","bool":true},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"In which stage of meiosis does pairing of homologous chromosomes occur?","answers":[{"option":"Pachytene","bool":false},{"option":"Zygotene","bool":true},{"option":"Diplotene","bool":false},{"option":"Leptotene","bool":false},{"option":"Metaphase-1","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Joint is a junction between 2 or more bones. It is mostly stabilized by which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrous capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Synovial membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Bursae","bool":false},{"option":"Ligament","bool":true}]},{"id":111,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What is the hallmark of irreversible injury?","answers":[{"option":"Cellular blebbing","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Cellular swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of proteins","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which type of epithelium lines trachea?","answers":[{"option":"Transitional","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar","bool":true},{"option":"Stratified cuboidal","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which type of transport is involved in the transport mechanism of the sodium-potassium pump?","answers":[{"option":"Bulk transport","bool":false},{"option":"Active transport","bool":true},{"option":"Osmosis","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Diffusion","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following refers to the gradual decrease in responsiveness due to repeated administration of the drug?","answers":[{"option":"Tachyphylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Tolerance","bool":true},{"option":"Placebo effect","bool":false},{"option":"Idiosyncrasy","bool":false},{"option":"Hypersensitivity","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which type of epithelium is found in the epidermis?","answers":[{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinized","bool":true},{"option":"Simple columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar ciliated","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following ions are not transported through the secondary active transport?","answers":[{"option":"Na+ and glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ and K+","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ and H+","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ and Ca+2","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which feature of the urinary bladder prevents the urine from leaking?","answers":[{"option":"Multiple layers of epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Anchoring junctions","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Occluding junctions","bool":true},{"option":"Transitional epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following initiates depolarization?","answers":[{"option":"Opening of slow K channels","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid movement of Ca out of cells","bool":false},{"option":"Change in membrane permeability","bool":true},{"option":"Closing of Na channels","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid movement of K out of cells","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"What does the term pyknosis mean?","answers":[{"option":"Condensation of chromatin","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear death","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear fragmentation","bool":false},{"option":"Dissolution of nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear shrinkage","bool":true}]},{"id":120,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which anomaly occurs as a result of remnants of primitive streak?","answers":[{"option":"Spina bifida","bool":false},{"option":"Open neuropore","bool":false},{"option":"Sacrococcygeal teratoma","bool":true},{"option":"Anencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Meromelia","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"A histologist is studying a component of connective tissue that has cells, fibers, and connective tissue. Which of the following connective tissues is he studying?","answers":[{"option":"Loose","bool":true},{"option":"Dense regular","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular","bool":false},{"option":"Adipose tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Dense irregular","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following principles makes certain that all the patients are given the same amount of care and resources?","answers":[{"option":"Efficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Beneficence","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomy","bool":false},{"option":"Justice","bool":true},{"option":"Non-maleficence","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"In a habitual smoker, how will the respiratory epithelium of conducting part change?","answers":[{"option":"From stratified columnar to stratified cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"From ciliated columnar to stratified squamous","bool":true},{"option":"From simple columnar to simple cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"From stratified cuboidal to stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"From stratified cuboidal to stratified squamous","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is correct for isoenzymes?","answers":[{"option":"Encoded by same genes","bool":false},{"option":"Catalyze the same reaction","bool":true},{"option":"Have same structure","bool":false},{"option":"Have same physical properties","bool":false},{"option":"Have same chemical properties","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is a characteristic for cardiac muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Multinucleated","bool":false},{"option":"Specialized cell junctions","bool":true},{"option":"Non-striated","bool":false},{"option":"Voluntary","bool":false},{"option":"Fusiform shape","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Pharmacodynamics is the study of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Assimilation of drugs","bool":false},{"option":"Absorption of drugs","bool":false},{"option":"Action of drugs on body","bool":true},{"option":"Metabolism of drugs","bool":false},{"option":"Excretion of drugs","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following is the characteristic of smooth muscle?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Intercalated discs","bool":false},{"option":"Multi-nucleated","bool":false},{"option":"Fusiform shape","bool":true},{"option":"Gap junctions","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which is the major plasma protein that helps to transport substances and maintains osmotic pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Haptoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":true},{"option":"Globulin","bool":false},{"option":"C-reactive protein","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which tumor suppressor gene checks and controls the transition from the G1 to S phase of the cell cycle?","answers":[{"option":"RB","bool":true},{"option":"p53","bool":false},{"option":"BCL-2","bool":false},{"option":"K-Ras","bool":false},{"option":"NF1","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2021","question":"Which of the following attributes is not correct for microtubules?","answers":[{"option":"Microtubules are components of centrioles and basal bodies","bool":false},{"option":"They are the primary structural component of flagella","bool":false},{"option":"Mediates movement of chromosomes","bool":false},{"option":"Microtubules are the thick filaments of sarcomeres","bool":true},{"option":"They help to control movements of subcellular particles","bool":false}]}]
export default arr